TARYN LYTLE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT



812-345-9791



tarlytle@gmail.com



github.com/TarynL



Taryn-Lytle

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Javascript
- C#
- HTML
- .NET
- CSS
- SQL
- React
- GitHub

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Excellent written, oral and interpersonal communication
- Ability to multitask, work in a fast paced environment while maintaining a high level of attention to accuracy
- Stable and progressive work history
- Successful in building and motivating dynamic teams
- Organized and detail-oriented
- Ability to work independently and partner with others to promote a positive work environment

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL Software Developer

INDIANA UNIVERSITY Telecommunications

ABOUT

I am an ex-axe throwing general manager who decided to holster my hatchets in order to embark on a new career in web development. I have enjoyed building reliable, attentive teams and creating a positive environment for customers to enjoy and am looking forward to combining my past experience with my new found skills in the technology world. Every day that goes by of learning, reassures me that I have made the best possible decision for my future.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Software Developer | Feb 2021 - Aug 2021 Rigorious six-month full-stack development bootcamp

- Worked remotely with teams as well as independently
- Utilized GitHub for code control and collaboration
- Created single page applications using multiple tech stacks including HTML, CSS, Javascript and React

PROJECTS

RecyclePedia-Front End Capstone | View Code

Single page application to show users what to recycle and how to do it properly, with drop off locations and tips on going zero waste.

- Built with HTML, React, CSS, Bootstrap, JSON Server and External API
- Ability to edit notes, delete and add new recyclables to the public list
- Toggle feature allows user to add/remove items from their list

Nutshell-React | View Code

Worked with 3 others to create an application for users to organize their daily tasks, events, news articles, friends and chat messages.

- Single page application with full CRUD functionality
- Utilized React and API calls to JSON server
- Implemented the private message and article components

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FLYING AXES

Axe Throwing Venue | General Manager | Jan 2017 - Sept 2020

- Successfully opened 2 locations, hiring, training and managing all staff
- Assisted in operations of each department within the company
- Networked within the community to create partnerships for special events and promotions

THE HUB

Restaurant/Cocktail Bar | Lead Bartender | Dec 2016 - Dec 2017

- Set good examples of staff conduct by following all house policies
 - Successfully trained multiple new hires
 - Fostered a positive work environment for my colleagues and patrons, helping to reduce employee turnover and encourage customer loyalty